准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
又到了新一期
It's time for another
海绵宝宝特辑
SpongeBob SquarePants special
但这次的特辑不一般
But it's not an ordinary special
因为今天不仅要去加利福尼亚恩斯诺
because today we go to Encino, California
而且要穿越回
as it was
一亿年以前
100,000,000 years ago
所以大家准备好收看
So prepare yourself for
海绵史传
史前笑传
有请主持人  海盗派斯
With your host, Patchy the Pirate
小朋友们
Hey, kids
你们大概心里正纳闷
Now, you're probably wondering
派斯在山洞里干什么
"What's Patchy doing in a cave?"
问得好  小东西
Good question, you little
因为今天这期海绵宝宝
Well, it's because today's SpongeBob
剧情可是发生在史前时代
takes place in prehistoric times
那时候人类还在艰难求生存
back when man struggled for survival
而统治全地球的则是恐龙
and dinosaurs ruled the earth
对不对啊  布朗提
Isn't that right, Bronty?
但现在换我骑你了
But I'm riding you now
卡住了
Stuck
救我出来
Get me out
救命  救命
Help, help
请稍候
我刚刚说到
Like I was saying
史前时代好得不能再好了
prehistoric times were the greatest
那个时代更简单  乐趣也简单
It was a simpler time, with simpler pleasures
穿搭早就提前搭好了
Your clothes always matched
往墙上乱画都不会有人骂
You could draw on the walls and nobody would yell at you
棒球还更好打了
It was much easier to hit a baseball
没错  史前时代最棒
Oh, yeah, prehistoric times were the best
小朋友们
Hey, kids
外面是传来了翼龙拍翅膀的声音吗
are those pterodactyl wings I hear a-flapping?
我应该知道是谁来了
I think I know who that is
请欢迎  翼龙波蒂
Please welcome the Potty-dactyl
抱歉迟到了
Sorry I'm late
你怎么不穿戏服
Why aren't you wearing your costume?
我好不容易通宵做出来的
I stayed up all night making it
你在浪费你时间  老东西
You're wasting your time, old man
史前时代太土了
Prehistoric stuff is lame
众所周知  未来才是王道
Everybody knows the future's where's it at
什么
What?
才不对
That's not true
大家别理他
Don't mind him, folks
就连海绵宝宝都知道史前特别
Why, even SpongeBob SquarePants
knows that prehistoric stuff is
小朋友怎么说的来着
What do the kids say?
酷
cool
才不知道
No, he doesn't
他知道
Yes, he does
不知道
No
肯定知道
He most certainly does
才不知道
No, he doesn't
他知道
Yes, he does
不知道
No
我知道他肯定知道
I know for a fact that he does
不知道
Not
同时
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
怎么了
What's wrong?
说不清  蟹老板
I don't know, Mr. Krabs
但我有种特别奇怪的感觉
But I've got the strangest feeling
某处有个海盗跟鹦鹉在吵我的事
that somewhere a pirate and parrot
are arguing about me
鹦鹉快吵赢了
And the parrot is winning
知道
Does
不知道
Doesn't
知道
Does
不知道
Doesn't
知道
Does
不知道
Doesn't
知道
Does
我们吵架期间呢
Look, while we're arguing
要不你们就来
why don't you folks go ahead
看点史前海绵宝宝吧
and watch some prehistoric SpongeBob
播动画片
Roll the cartoon
知道
Does
不知道
Doesn't
呃
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
黎明降临原始海洋
Dawn breaks over the primordial sea
数百万年以前  正是在这儿
It is here that millions of years ago
生命离开黑暗  踏出了笨拙的一步
life began taking its first clumsy steps
out of the darkness
睁开了业已形成的眼睛
opening its newly formed eyeballs
望向了耀眼夺目的智慧之光
to stare into the blinding light of intelligence
为了
in order to
当我没说
Never mind
这是很久以前的事了
This happened a long time ago
我准备好了
Banooga ready
[ Banooga ready：I'm ready ]
走了  小蜗
Tabonga, Gary
[ Tabonga：come on ]
小蜗
Gary
快走
Tabonga
先等一下
Wait a minute
海绵嘎
SpongeGar
海绵嘎  你看看
SpongeGar, manaka
[ Manaka：look ]
不准留下小蜗的黏液
No tabonga Gary pooga
[ Tabonga：left
Pooga：slime ]
走过来留下一大条乱糟糟的黏液
Tabonga as a go o saila
[ Go o：messy
Salia：trail ]
你的不是我的
Tabanga-do
[ Tabanga-do：it belongs to you, not me ]
你的不是我的
Tabanga-do
Tabanga-do?
你的不是我的
Tabanga-do
你的
Tabanga
不准留下小蜗的黏液
No tabanga Gary pooga
你的不是我的
Tabanga-do
派星嘎
Pathar
好吃
Mowanga
[ Mowanga：excellent ]
派星嘎
Pathar
章鱼嘎
Squag
派星嘎爱章鱼嘎
Pathar unga Squag
[ Unga：love ]
章鱼嘎
Squag
派星嘎
Pathar
海绵嘎
SpongeGar
派星嘎
Pathar
海绵嘎跟派星嘎没脑子
SpongeGar and Pathar no got malonka polinka
[ Malonka：any
Polinka：brain ]
脑子
Polinka
海绵嘎跟派星嘎疯了
Pathar and SpongeGar bawannagog
[ Bawannagog：crazy ]
不关章鱼嘎的事
No pooca Squag
[ Pooca：bother ]
章鱼嘎要创造天才杰作
Squag tay taila foo
[ Tay：make
Talia foo：genius ]
派星嘎
Pathar
海绵嘎
SpongeGar
花花
Fongar
[ Fongar：flower ]
傻子
Monga
[ Monga：stupid ]
海绵嘎
SpongeGar
派星嘎  滚开
Pathar, chonga
[ Chonga：go away ]
章鱼嘎  章鱼嘎
Squag, Squag
给海绵嘎
Tooka SpongeGar?
[ Tooka：give ]
好吃
Yum
天才  海绵嘎
Taila foo, SpongeGar
天才
Taila foo
海绵嘎不是笨蛋
SpongeGar na dumbo
派星嘎
Pathar
看海绵嘎
Wa SpongeGar
[ Wa：watch ]
钱  钱
Money, money
万岁
Hooray
看来我们的史前好朋友
It looks like our prehistoric pals
刚刚发现了火
have just discovered fire
但他们马上就会学到
But they will soon learn
玩火会自焚
that when you play with fire, you may get burned
不要走开
Stay tuned
就说史前时代很好玩吧
I told you prehistoric times were fun
要不要我来教教大家
How's about I teach you kids
原始人用两根棍是怎么生火的
how a cavemen makes a fire with two sticks?
好
Yeah
酷到不能再酷了对不对
Doesn't get any cooler than that, huh?
派斯加一分
Chalk one up for Patchy
史前
摩擦
Rubbing
这种木头貌似烧不着
I guess this is the wood that doesn't burn
波蒂
Potty
激光科技
Laser technology
未来加一分
Score one for the future
未来
我有样东西
Well, I got something
你未来那边肯定找不到
that you'll never find in your little "future"
活生生的真原始人
a real, live caveman
他来了
There he is
进来啊  穴居原始人
Come on in, big troglodyte fellow
进来啊
Come on
小朋友  我是在一大块冰里找到他的
You see, kids, I found him frozen in a block of ice
然后我又花了三天的时间
and then I spent three days
用我妈的吹风机帮他解冻
thawing him out with my mom's hair dryer
我给他取名叫洞哥
I call him Cavey
是不是很厉害
Isn't he something?
没事的  洞哥
It's okay, Cavey
微不足道  老东西
That's nothing, Old Timer
给未来让个道
Make way for the future
你好
Greetings
我是X29488
I am the X29488
需要什么服务
How may I serve you?
你上哪找来那么多破玩意的
Where do you keep getting all this stuff?
关你屁事  老东西
Never you mind, Pops
不如看洞哥怎么说
Let's go see what Cavey thinks
进攻
Attack
波蒂
Potty
你把我的原始人节目毁了
You're ruining my caveman show
进攻
Attack
派斯还能夺回特辑的主动权吗
Will Patchy ever get control of the special?
海绵宝宝会用火做什么呢
What will SpongeBob do with fire?
继续收看海绵史传
Stay tuned to SpongeBob SquarePants B.C.
海绵史传
史前笑传
就知道了
and find out
欢迎继续收看海绵史传
Welcome back to SpongeBob SquarePants B.C.
派斯这边的情况变得一发不可收拾了
Sounds like things have gone
from bad to worse for Patchy
来看看吧
Let’s watch
进攻
Attack
太好看了
This is great
大家好
Ahoy
很高兴你们回来了
Glad you're back
继续看完海绵史传吧
Let's watch the rest of SpongeBob B.C.
我先把事情收拾干净
while I get things straightened out around here
也
Or
可能收拾不了
maybe not
进攻
Attack
先前我们看到这群饿肚子原始人
When we last saw our hungry troglodytes
刚刚发现了火
they'd just discovered fire
他们还要多久才会搞出烂摊子呢
How long will it take for them to mess it up?
一起看
Let's see
钱  钱
Money, money
打嗝
Bolapa
[ Bolapa：burp ]
晚安  派星嘎
Ganoga, Patar
[ Ganoga：good night ]
晚安  海绵嘎
Ganoga, SpongeGar
晚安  章鱼嘎
Ganoga, Squag
晚安  海绵嘎
Ganoga, SpongeGar
晚安  章鱼嘎
Ganoga, Squag
晚安  派星嘎
Ganoga, Patar
章鱼嘎不要玩火
No Squag fwee fwee
海绵嘎玩火
SpongeGar fwee fwee
海绵嘎  休想
SpongeGar fagonda
[ Fagonda：forget it ]
派星嘎
Pathar
笨蛋派星嘎
Dumbo Pathar
章鱼嘎玩火
Fwee fwee Squag
派星嘎
Pathar
给我  派星嘎
Babwana, Pathar
给我
Babwana
派星嘎玩火
Pathar fwee fwee
章鱼嘎玩火
Fwee fwee Squag
派星嘎玩火
Pathar fwee fwee
海绵嘎玩火
SpongeGar fwee fwee
火跑下来了
Fwee fwee go bonga
[ Bonga：down ]
海绵嘎玩火
SpongeGar fwee fwee
章鱼嘎玩火
Squag fwee fwee
派星嘎玩火
Pathar fwee fwee
派星嘎
Pathar
海绵嘎
SpongeGar?
派星嘎
Oh, Pathar
海绵嘎
Oh, SpongeGar
好你个小鬼
Sutaka jakasa
[ Sutaka jakasa：Why you little ]
你的不是我的
Tabanga-do
也许某些历史事件
Perhaps certain events in history
还是不说比较好
are better left untold
现在我能理解章鱼哥什么感受了
Now I know how Squidward feels
干嘛苦瓜脸
Why the long face?
你自己心知肚明  你个坏鸟
I think you know
perfectly well, you little wingèd vermin
我就只想给各位观众看看
All I wanted was to show the nice people
原始人有多厉害
how great the cavemen were
结果放出来的全是高科技惹的祸
But all they got was technology-induced chaos
快进来吧
Come back inside
你一定会特别惊喜的
I think you'll be pleasantly surprised
你把机器人赶走了吗
You got rid of the robot android cyborg?
不对  比那强
No, even better
波蒂  我应该是真的看错你了
Potty, I guess I really misjudged you
怎么
What the?
当世界相撞
When worlds collide
是不是很棒
Pretty sweet, eh?
可以逃得走
You can run
但是躲不掉
but you can't hide
当世界相撞
When worlds collide
会变特好笑
You'll laugh so hard
可以笑死你
You'll swear you've died
当世界相撞
When worlds collide
牵住我的手  让我当导游
Hold my hand, I'll be your guide
当世界相撞
When worlds collide
系好  系好
Buckle, buckle
系好安全带  一起去路上
buckle up for the sweetest ride
快准备好要来欣喜若狂
And prepare to have your mind blown wide
当世界相撞
When worlds collide
来看看
Check it out
当世界相撞  有点不寻常
When worlds collide, it's a curious thing
机器人原始人合唱前所未见
Bet you never heard a robot and a caveman sing
他的金属胸膛里面尽是些零件
In his metal chest are some working parts
跟我的心脏又能有啥不一样
How is that different from my beating heart?
我来自未来
I'm from the future
我来自过去
And I'm from the past
不代表这场友情
But that don't mean this friendship
维持不下去
Wasn't built to last
实验室里造了他
He was made in a lab
山洞里生了我
And I was born in a cave
这场跨时代锐舞会让你欢呼尖叫
So let me hear you holler for this inter-era rave
未来
Future
支持
Word
我是机器宝宝
I am SpongeTron
可  可
You, you
可以逃得走
you can run
但是躲不掉
But you can't hide
当世界相撞
When worlds collide
波蒂  你说得确实
Well, Potty, I guess you were right
未来的确很酷
The future is cool
只是想让你别太在意
Just to show you there's no hard feelings
我要送你份史前大礼
I got you a present from the prehistoric times
什么礼物  新遮羞布吗
What is it, a new loincloth?
错
No
超大额骨吗
An enlarged forehead?
错
No
那又是什么
What is it?
波蒂
Potty
冷饮
太好看了
This is great
感谢小朋友们收看海绵史传
Well, thanks for watching SpongeBob B.C., kids
再见
Bye
现在还挠痒痒了
Now he's tickling
别闹了  小坏蛋
Cut it out, you rascal